WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.MY-SUBS.com --
I need your oath.
The first traces of a new ore.
Elrond has been very
convincing in his assurances
that Gil-galad bore no ill
intent when he sent him here.
There is something more at work.
Go to Lindon. Find out what.
You're off the Sea Guard! All three of you!
Enough!
I just ruined my friends' lives,
shamed our family name.
Go to the Men who have taken
refuge in the old watchtower.
Deliver to them a message.
That your people may live if you
forsake all claim to these lands
and swear fealty to him.
One day, our true king will return.
I believe the man you
hold in your dungeons
is the lost heir in exile
to the throne of the Southlands.
I call on you to fight with me...
- I will serve!
...before Sauron claims
their lands for his own.
You have lied, brought a
dangerous outsider into our midst.
We're going to be left behind.
This is how we keep up with the others.
He helps us, and... and we help him.
My great thumb. My great thumb.
No. Mi... Migration.
Like, mi-gra-tion.
Means, like, to move.
What we do, Harfoots.
You see, we... we winter in Old Forest,
and mid-summer, we make for Norfield Glen
to snail while the snailing's good.
- "Snails, snails"?
- Snails, yeah.
And at the first blush of the
oak leaves, we head to the Grove.
A whole orchard,
popping with bar apples, plums,
apricots, carrots,
you'll... you'll love it.
Of course, the only trouble is there's
a hundred perils between here and there.
"Perils"?
Like a danger.
You know, big folk, wolves, fog, rain,
hill-trolls, cave-trolls,
anything that'll kill ya.
"Kill"?
Means to make somethin' dead.
I'm peril.
No. No, no, you're not.
- It's more...
- No. Fireflies.
That was just an accident. It's...
You're not a peril.
You're good.
I'm good?
You're good. Because
you're here to help.
Nori!
Oh, great. Others
should be ready by now.
Quick sticks!
Let's go. Come on.
I... I'm...
I'm good.
Poke me with that crutch again,
I'll pluck the hair off
your toes in your sleep.
And I'll pluck off my
ears while you're at it.
It'd save me listenin' to your snorin'.
Oh, stuff. I do not snore.
Yes, you do.
Come on, now. Grove's
not gonna migrate to us.
Might help us move faster if you
sang us your mam's walking song.
Yeah, go on, Pops, give us a warble.
Oh, come on, it'll do us some good.
♪ The sun is fast fallin' ♪
♪ Beneath trees of stone ♪
♪ The light in the tower ♪
♪ No longer my home ♪
♪ Past eyes of pale fire ♪
♪ Black sand for my bed ♪
♪ I trade all I've known ♪
♪ For the unknown ahead ♪
♪ Call to me ♪
♪ Call to me lands far away ♪
♪ For I must now wander this wandering day ♪
♪ Away I must wander ♪
♪ This wandering day ♪
♪ Of drink I have little ♪
♪ And food I have less ♪
♪ My strength tells me no ♪
♪ But the path demands yes ♪
♪ My legs are so short ♪
♪ And the way is so long ♪
♪ I've no rest nor comfort ♪
♪ No comfort, but song ♪
♪ Sing to me, sing to me ♪
♪ Lands far away ♪
♪ Oh, rise up and guide me ♪
♪ This wandering day ♪
♪ Please promise to find me ♪
♪ At last comes their answer ♪
♪ Through cold and through frost ♪
♪ That not all who wonder
or wander are lost ♪
♪ No matter the sorrow ♪
♪ No matter the cost ♪
♪ That not all who wonder ♪
♪ Or wander are... ♪
♪ Lost ♪
The tunnel is complete, my lord.
Your arm. Show it to me.
How does it feel?
Like fire, Lord-father.
I wish you could feel it like I do.
For soon, it will be gone.
And with it, the part of me
that knew its warmth as well.
I shall miss it.
Summon the legions. It is time.
Our enemy vows to attack.
In exchange for mercy,
we've been ordered to abandon this tower
and swear fealty to their commander.
I know I'm not the
king you have awaited.
But if you choose to
stand with me and fight,
this tower will no longer
be a reminder of our frailty,
but a symbol of our strength.
Who will stand with me?
Who among you will stand and fight?
- Aye, let's do it.
- Aye.
Stand and fight?
You will die.
I say it'd be better to take our chances
bowing to the supposed enemy.
I have looked that enemy in the eye.
He's not your deliverance.
You think you are?
Elf?
I'll say this for our ancestors.
They lived!
Together, we can survive this.
Follow me, and together, we will!
Come on. Let's go.
Come on. Follow me. Come on!
Come on!
Follow me!
Theo!
It's our chance. It's our time. Come on.
With me. Come on, lad. Follow me, lad.
Right. Okay. Give me a hand, will ya?
Higher. Higher!
Enough for that run, lads.
Ferry it out now.
- Father.
- Isildur.
May we speak?
Why wasn't I chosen for the expedition?
- Thought you were going west.
- Not anymore.
Not till I've done
something worthy of Númenor.
And what is that? In your words.
I don't have words for it.
That's why I'm trying
so hard to find it.
Why I'm asking for your help.
Wish I could provide it.
But we've far more volunteers than
we could ever hope to accommodate.
Half the city wants
a spot on those boats.
Slip me to the front of the line.
What are your qualifications?
- "Qualifications"?
- Do you belong to the Sea Guard?
- You know I'm twice the sailor...
What about the Queen's
Guard? Merchant's Guild?
- This is about uniform.
- Horseman's Guild?
You're being absurd.
While you were feigning fidelity
to the traditions of this isle,
these men were living them.
Finding ways to contribute. To serve.
Something of which you
evidently care little.
I care. I'm ready to serve.
Nothing would make me prouder.
But you had your chance.
And you made your choice.
Risk Númenorean lives
for some grimy Southlander
and a warmongering Elf?
Consul Pharazôn!
Why are you sending
our kinsmen off to die?
Pharazôn! Pharazôn!
- Pharazôn!
- Come with me.
Forgive me for not sending word
to you sooner. Been a trying week.
Why didn't he stop this?
- He's loyal to her. Rightly or...
- Wrongly.
There are many who feel as you do.
Not enough to sway him yet,
but given the right push...
Then it must be you. He will listen to you.
When I speak, his ears close up.
So speak louder.
Oi, Southlander.
You have visitors.
And where did the enemy head next?
Further south, I should think.
Towards the watchtower of Ostirith.
I'll inform the Sea Guard.
My thanks, Lord Halbrand.
I'm certain your fellowship will prove
just as invaluable
once we make landfall.
"Landfall?"
Galadriel informed us of your
aspiration to unite your people.
Did she now?
I trust she was not speaking in haste?
As a matter of fact,
it was my intention...
My companion is merely
feeling the weight of his task.
I have no doubt, come
time, he will do his part.
Given that I've staked my
name upon it, I should hope so.
Queen Regent, your father has
requested your presence in the tower.
"Galadriel informed us."
I wondered how the queen knew to
waylay me at her father's bedside.
It never occurred to me you'd
hand me over for a guild crest.
You used me. After I all
but begged you to let me be.
I have just convinced
Númenor to send five ships
and 500 men to aid your people
and place a crown upon your head.
Many might assume you used me.
Find another head to crown.
I don't like it here.
Oh, it's okay, Dil. It's just the trees.
What madness made them go this way?
Rockfoot Pass must be blocked in.
Won't get any easier in
the dark. Keep movin'.
"Easier in the dark."
Wolves.
Why don't you tell
me what's really goin' on?
These woods have never been
this bare this time of year.
It's as plain as lip fungus.
He is responsible,
isn't he? The big fella.
What precisely do you
expect me to do about it?
What you ought to have done at the camp.
Take their wheels and leave them!
What's it gonna take?
Make a widow of somebody?
Or an orphan?
People are gettin' hungry.
Stay close.
Hmm.
Oh, this is very strange. Most peculiar.
Most peculiar.
Oh!
- You nearly caused my heart to burst.
- Malva.
- We saw footprints.
- In the mud.
- Lots of 'em!
- One at a time, please!
Run!
Come on! Run!
Nori!
Nori! Nori!
Nori, get away from there!
No! It'll get you!
Hold your ground, Ontamo.
Make your father proud.
Their strokes fall like the
Stone-giants of the North Moors.
And yet?
They are untested against this foe.
Perhaps the Elf would be willing
to offer some instructions?
There are many ways to kill an Orc.
But for you, I will keep
it strong and simple.
Stab, twist, gut.
Come at me.
We will see who can score flesh.
Anyone that does, I will promote...
To lieutenant.
Swordsmanship is about
balance, rather than strength.
Fight with your feet. Not your arms.
The Elf is fighting
a soldier in the square.
Don't plant roots.
Keep moving.
Never trust brute force to best an Orc.
It's often easiest to outmaneuver them.
Well done, Lieutenant.
Never known a smith's
aide who could do that.
It's not too late to stop this.
Your cousin may hold the scepter,
but it's you the people follow.
- With their help you could...
- Could what?
Assert your influence.
Sometimes the folly of youth is
enough to make an old man weep.
Is it folly to try and stop a war?
It's folly to kick against the current.
You see, the tide may
rise and drown a man,
or fall and sweep him out to sea.
The trick of mastering the current is
to know which way it will turn next.
You all but single-handedly
prevented our last king
from dragging us back to the old ways.
Don't tell me you couldn't
sway Míriel's mind now.
And what makes you think Míriel's mind
and my own are not as one on this?
Because my father would sooner
die than take orders from an Elf.
"Orders from an Elf"?
When all this has ended,
Elves will take orders from us.
Now, my cousin can go to war
for Galadriel if she wishes.
I go to war for Númenor.
How could this be for Númenor?
Have you learned nothing?
Soon, we will save the
low men of Middle-earth,
lift them up, and give them
the king they've long awaited.
A king who will be forever in our debt.
Now, contemplate, if you can,
how that might benefit us.
Ores, forests, trades, tribute...
I wouldn't dare stop that. Not
for all the salt in the sea.
And neither should you.
The kingdom!
- The kingdom is in danger. I must...
- The danger has passed, Father.
We are doing now what you
always believed we must.
We're restoring our
connection with the Elves.
I'm going to Middle-earth.
Míriel?
Yes, Father.
It's me.
Don't go to Middle-earth.
All that awaits you there is...
What, Father? What awaits me?
Darkness.
Can you believe it?
Everyone's talkin' about what you did.
Never seen 'em take a shine to
an outsider like this before.
Brought you some beeswax.
Slather some on that paw,
should help with the tenderness.
Hey.
Stop. Please.
To an enduring union
between our two great peoples,
Khazad and Noldor.
- To the union.
Before our wines ascend,
Lord Durin, I should
like to commend you.
Khazad-dûm has been called the
quietest of Dwarven kingdoms,
but in recent months, your
furnaces are said to be burning
as bright as the eyes of Aulë himself.
Your mines delving ever deeper.
To what do you credit
this new invigoration?
I might ask the same of Lindon.
Shipping off its warriors, expandin' its cities.
Bit sudden for Elves, no?
Typically takes you people weeks
just to decide to take a sh...
If I may...
The hand of time crawls
so slowly for our kind.
We often overlook the years of effort
we perceive as taking but a moment.
In so doing, I would not
wish to offend our guest.
I would think our Dwarven
friend far too stout of heart
to be offended by an honest inquiry.
I have an honest inquiry for you.
From where did you procure the table?
Why do you ask?
This stone grows only at certain depths.
So rarely do our
resonators locate a deposit.
We consider each to be a precious gift.
We reserve its use for
the most sacred purposes.
Monuments or tombs,
to our honored dead.
Please forgive our
sacrilege, Lord Durin.
We shall have to send it home with you,
so it can be treated
with proper respect.
It's good to know there's still
some honor left among the Elves.
Your Grace.
To the union of our two peoples, then.
To the union.
Your loyalty to the Dwarf is admirable.
Loyalty to a friend
ought to be expected.
Regardless of his race.
Does it justify lying to your king?
I wonder, High King, if it is in
fact you who has been lying to me.
I went to Khazad-dûm with a
proposal of friendship, but in truth,
you sought something far
more tangible, didn't you?
Are you familiar with The Song
of the Roots of Hithaeglir?
Recount it for me, please.
An obscure legend regarded
by most to be a apocryphal.
Recount it, Elrond Peredhel.
It speaks of a battle,
high among the peaks
of the Misty Mountains.
Not over honor or duty. But over a tree.
Within which some claim was hidden
the last of the lost Silmarils.
On one side, fought an Elven warrior,
with a heart as pure as Manwë,
who poured all of his light
into the tree to protect it.
On the other, a Balrog of Morgoth,
who channeled all his hatred
into the tree to destroy it.
Amidst their duel unending,
lightning ensnared the tree...
Forging of their conflict, a power...
A power as pure and light as good.
As strong and unyielding as evil.
They say it seeped down the
roots into the mountain depths,
where for centuries now, it has waited.
Durin was right.
Then you admit the Dwarves did find it.
The ore containing the
light of the lost Silmaril.
I admit only this.
I promised Durin never to
reveal his people's secrets.
And what if keeping your
promise to his people
meant ensuring the doom of your own?
We first took notice of it just
prior to Galadriel's return.
We hoped that by sending her away,
and so bringing an end to
the last vestiges of war,
we might arrest the decay.
But despite our every effort,
our decline has only quickened.
The blight upon this tree
is but an outer manifestation
of an inner reality.
That the light of the Eldar,
our light, is fading.
Who else knows about this?
Precious few.
I ask again, and for the last time,
did the Dwarves find the ore or not?
I swore an oath to Durin.
To some, that may now
hold little weight.
But in my esteem,
it is by such things
our very souls are bound.
I do not intend to let mine slip
away on the basis of mere hope.
Hope is never mere, Elrond...
even when it is meager.
When all other senses sleep,
the eye of hope is first
to awaken, last to shut.
If the Elves abandon Middle-earth now,
the armies of darkness will
march over the face of the earth.
It will be the end,
not just of our people, but all peoples.
If the hope of preventing
that is not reason enough
to make you reconsider your oath,
I suggest you find another.
♪ What was the land immortal hands ♪
♪ Rose up from Sundering Sea? ♪
♪ Land of the gift, land of the star ♪
♪ To shine eternally? ♪
♪ 'Twas Númenor Fair Númenor ♪
♪ Bright isle filled with grace... ♪
I said it won't be dangerous.
I wager it'll all be over by
the time I get off the boat.
Just don't tell my father.
He keeps crowing to everyone with ears,
his future son-in-law's a war hero.
Sing! Come on, sing.
You remember the words, don't you?
After hearing you squawk them all
night, I fear I'll never forget them.
Perhaps Isildur will sing with you.
♪ Oh, bless our every breath... ♪
This should be interesting.
♪ Make our great land to ever stand ♪
♪ Our swords to conquer death ♪
- The answer's no.
- I haven't said anything yet.
I've known you 15 years.
You think I don't know
what you're here to say?
- It's actually 16, but I mean...
- Ontamo.
Right. What have I come to say?
A fairly lavish apology,
which Ontamo, of course,
would've accepted instantly,
but I wouldn't have.
And do you know why?
You're only apologizing because you
think now that I've been promoted,
I can get you on the expedition.
- Can you?
- Right.
I'd just like to say, I
wouldn't have accepted instantly.
- But I am glad that you apologized.
- No, he didn't.
I did!
But I'll gladly do it again.
I'm sorry I started the fight.
Now please bring me with you.
No.
What'll it take to make this right?
Fine, you get a free hit.
Jaw, gut, your choice. One hit.
Three.
Uh, two.
Actually...
That felt like three.
So, you'll bring me on the ship?
Isildur, you're my oldest friend.
And if you want to know the truth,
you're probably still my best, but...
- What?
- Ontamo, please.
I can't, in good
conscience, stake my name
recommending you for a duty that
you might well decide to abandon.
- It'll be different this time.
- Hmm.
One day, I hope it will be.
One day, I hope you find something
that you would be willing
to sacrifice anything for.
I'll take care of Berek
for you. I promise.
Berek's going?
The horsemaster recruited him.
Sorry, Isil. The sea is always right.
Are you stowing away?
Are you about to burn the boat?
Get out of here this moment. I
won't let anyone know I saw you.
- Hand me the lantern.
- Don't.
Give it.
Gather every hand. Hurry!
Get them out. Quickly.
Get them out! Isildur?
Isildur?
What happened?
He was in a fishing boat.
A cask must've gone up.
A cask?
He saved my life.
He could've just left,
but he saved my life.
Captain!
We have reason to
suspect a passing brigand,
but we've yet to identify him.
We're fortunate we didn't lose
the rest of the ships as well.
This was clearly an attempt to
kindle your doubts, Queen Regent.
- Do not let it.
- I'm forced to disagree with the Elf.
Perhaps we did act in haste.
A kingdom should be led. Not dragged.
I recommend we delay the voyage
until we've had time enough to
win more hearts to your cause.
Our enemy grows stronger every
day. Perhaps every hour we hesitate.
Remember why you chose this
path. Remember your faith.
Do you think I could forget?
- We still have three ships.
- And your father's blessing.
What of Lord Halbrand?
He awaits our departure.
I'm sure he does.
Shall I tell the Sea
Guard to stand down?
This council will reconvene at
first light to make a final decision.
See to it Lord Halbrand attends.
What have you been able to ascertain?
Elrond, forgive me.
Forgive you?
That I did not tell you sooner.
You knew.
I begged him to allow you into
our confidence from the start,
but the High King forbade it.
And this... this mithril...
It is our only salvation?
Elrond, I have tested
it under every duress.
Nothing diminishes its light.
We believe if we can secure
vast quantities of it quickly,
enough to saturate every last Elf
in the light of the Valar once more...
Then, yes.
Yes. It very well could be.
I am sorry.
That the High King deceived me?
Or that now our people are
doomed unless I break an oath?
And betray a friend?
I was there, Elrond, the
night your father set sail.
A mortal man, who believed he
could convince the very Gods
to come to war in our aid.
I heard your mother
pleading with him not to go,
asking him, imploring him,
why, why must it be him?
And do you know what he said?
Because he was the only
one who could do it.
I was wrong to use you.
For that, I'm sorry.
Tomorrow, the queen will
call you to audience.
Your voice at that
meeting may well decide
whether this mission stands or falls.
- Help me.
- I think I've helped you quite enough.
Then help yourself.
Stop fighting me, and
together, let us fight them.
Not so long ago, men like me
were fighting alongside them.
Men like you. Not you, yourself.
You're wrong.
You don't know what I did
before I ended up on that raft.
You don't know how I survived.
How we all survived.
And when these people discover
it, they will cast me out.
So will you.
Sometimes to find the light, we
must first touch the darkness.
What do you know of darkness?
Whose dagger was it, Galadriel?
Who is it you lost?
My brother.
What happened to him?
He was killed.
In a place of darkness and despair.
By servants of Sauron.
Is that enough for you?
So this is about vengeance?
One cannot satisfy thirst
by drinking seawater.
Then what is it? Why
do you keep fighting?
You are asking me to go to the one
place that I swore never to return.
The least you can do is tell me why.
Why do you keep fighting?
Because I cannot stop.
The company I led mutinied against me.
My closest friend conspired
with the king to exile me.
And each of them acted as they did...
Because I believe they could
no longer distinguish me...
from the evil I was fighting.
I'm sorry.
For your brother.
For all of it.
I'm sorry.
Your sorrow cannot ease my pain.
And nor will a hammer
and tongs ease yours.
There is no peace to
be found for you here.
And nor for me.
No lasting peace in any path,
but that which lies across the sea.
I have fought for centuries,
seeking to earn mine.
This is how you earn yours.
Long have I awaited this day.
The day your kind would return at last,
lift us up from the muck and the filth,
to take our rightful place at your side.
I pledge my undying service to you.
I pledge my loyalty to Sauron.
You are Sauron, are you not?
Hey, hey... Wait...
I'll serve you, then. Whoever you are.
Only blood can bind.
Waldreg?
Waldreg...
Waldreg, no.
No.
No!
Lift your aim next time.
And don't be so afraid of the string.
Why bother trying to teach me?
Because it took me over 200 years
to develop the bravery that's
keeping me standing here tonight.
You found it in only 14.
And we're going to need
it in the fight to come.
All my life, your kind has watched us.
Counting every whisper.
Every kitchen knife too sharp.
We're all about to be
buried in this tower.
So why be buried with us?
Because in counting the
whispers and the knives,
I've come to know the voices and
the hands of those behind them.
Half of us just left.
But half stayed.
Including you.
So lift your aim.
There's something you don't know.
I've seen this before.
It is a key.
Conjured by some forgotten
craft of the enemy,
to enslave your ancestors.
A key to what?
I do not know.
The enemy commander
spoke of becoming a god.
Of giving the Orcs a
home in these lands.
But whatever his design,
this much is certain.
Our enemy knows your son has
what he needs to enact it.
How long?
Days.
Maybe hours.
We can survive this, Bronwyn.
There is a way.
There must be.
There is one.
No! Bow to the enemy, and
you take away everything.
From your son, and his sons after him.
Your people have worked an entire
age to earn back their virtue.
Would you undo it all in
just one moment of despair?
There must be another way.
Name it. I beg you.
See?
You were right to watch us.
Because we are destined
for the darkness.
It's how we survive.
Perhaps it's who we are.
Who we will always be.
There's far more at stake
here than just our lives.
When Morgoth was at war,
whole continents sank.
Who is to say what
horrors this might unleash,
should our enemy obtain it?
What power do we have to stop him?
Look around. It's over.
- Not yet.
- Soon enough.
And when they march upon
us, this tower will fall.
Nampat!
You made it up, didn't you?
Disa's been wanting a
new table for years, so...
Ah, come on, it's not that heavy.
It is not the weight of
the table that burdens me.
So why don't you come out with it?
Because a burden shared may
either be halved or doubled.
Depending on the heart that receives it.
Aulë's beard! Enough with the quail sauce.
Give me the meat, and give it to me raw.
I have not been
truthful with you, Durin.
I did not come to Khazad-dûm
for friendship, but ambition.
I did not know it.
But I came for mithril.
Why?
Without it,
my kind must either abandon
these shores by spring, or perish.
Perish?
Perish how?
Our immortal souls will
dwindle into nothing,
slowly diminishing,
until we are but shadows,
swept away by the tides of time.
Forever.
So the fate of the entire
Elven race is in my hands?
So it would appear.
Say that again.
The fate of the entire
Elven race is in your hands.
Whose hands?
Yours.
Hmm.
Fetch your feathery
shirts. Let's start walking.
- Durin...
- Don't thank me yet.
Thank me after we find a
way to convince my father.
Now can we please get moving?
It's a long journey back.
And all this sunlight is startin'
to give me a sour stomach.
Under one condition.
Tell Disa the table's from me.
Don't push your luck, Elf.
Lord Halbrand, the
Queen Regent summons you.
Look whose father
secured him a post. Again.
I earned mine. Same as you.
Soldier.
Report to the horsemaster.
Thought I was in cavalry.
You are.
Stable sweep.
Soldiers!
Clear the lines!
Square the sail!
We head nor'-east.
For Middle-earth.
Yes!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.MY-SUBS.com --